<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://blog.emresaglam.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://blog.emresaglam.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-11-07T16:27:49-08:00</updated><id>https://blog.emresaglam.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">eBlog</title><subtitle>Emre&apos;s blog!</subtitle><author><name>Emre Sağlam</name></author><entry><title type="html">How to setup YSF2DMR on pi-star</title><link href="https://blog.emresaglam.com/general/ysf2dmr-setup/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to setup YSF2DMR on pi-star" /><published>2023-09-17T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-09-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://blog.emresaglam.com/general/ysf2dmr-setup</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.emresaglam.com/general/ysf2dmr-setup/"><![CDATA[<p>In this blog entry I will talk about setting up YSF2DMR on pi-star (on a generic MMDVM device). I’ll try to be brief and not too detailed.</p>

<h1 id="getting-a-dmr-id">Getting a DMR ID</h1>

<ol>
  <li>Go <a href="https://www.radioid.net/register">here</a> and get a DMR ID.</li>
  <li>Go <a href="https://brandmeister.network/?page=register">here</a> and get a Brandmeister login.</li>
  <li>Go <a href="https://help.brandmeister.us/dashboard/hotspot-security">here</a> and follow the instructions to get a Hotspot Security Password.</li>
</ol>

<h1 id="setting-up-pi-star">Setting up Pi-Star</h1>
<p>I will not talk about how to install pi-star, there are many good tutorials on the web. Always get the latest version of the pi-star software.</p>

<p>Go to pi-star Configuration page.</p>
<ol>
  <li>Toggle YSF Mode on</li>
  <li>Toggle YSF2DMR on</li>
  <li>Click on Apply Changes button. Wait for pi-star to apply the configuration.</li>
  <li>In the General Configuration section make sure that CCS7/DMR ID is populated with your Radio ID that you got after registering with Radio ID (Link Above).</li>
</ol>

<p><img src="/assets/ysf.png" alt="apply changes" /></p>

<h2 id="yaesu-section-configuration">Yaesu Section Configuration</h2>

<ol>
  <li>Under Yaesu System Fusion Configuration section:</li>
  <li>I usually leave the YSF Startup Host blank. But it really doesn’t matter. If you will use it JUST for YSF2DMR, then maybe you might want to leave it connected to: YSF00002 That’s the default YSF2DMR channel.</li>
  <li>Toggle UPPERCASE Hostfiles on</li>
  <li>Toggle WiresX Passthrough on (This one actually enables code not to be interpreted by the WiresX node, we will need this to be able to switch to a Talk Group on the fly)</li>
  <li>(YSF2DMR)CCS7/DMR ID field choose as 01</li>
  <li>DMR Master: Choose one server that is near you. I use BM 3103 as it’s close to me. That’s a Brandmeister server in the USA.</li>
  <li>Hotspot Security: Enter here the password that you created with Brandmeister as Hotspot Security. (Link Above)</li>
  <li>DMR TG: This is the ID for the Initial Talk Group that you want to connect. I usually leave this 00091. Talk Group for World Wide.</li>
  <li>Here apply the changes and you should be good to go.</li>
</ol>

<h1 id="setting-up-the-radio">Setting up the radio</h1>
<p>I’ll be talking about setting in Yaesu FT3D, but it is similar for most.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Dial the radio to the frequency that you set up under General Configuration -&gt; Radio Frequency.</li>
  <li>Press the X button (WiresX button).</li>
  <li>Once you connect the MMDVM, press Search &amp; Direct button.</li>
  <li>Then press the Search &amp; Direct button again (on the second screen)</li>
  <li>You will see an ID button on the top left. Press that. This will change the input to 5 digits only.</li>
  <li>Type the number: 00002 and press ENT. This will connect the MMDVM to YSF00002 room. This room is the YSF2DMR room.</li>
  <li>Then press Search &amp; Direct two times in two different screens again.</li>
  <li>And press ID again.</li>
  <li>From this point on you can only change Talk Group IDs. You will be in YSF2DMR (YSF00002) room but will be able to switch DMR Talk groups by entering their IDs.</li>
  <li>Try your first group something like 00091 (This is TG91 World-Wide DMR channel)</li>
  <li>Congrats! :)</li>
</ol>

<h1 id="some-tips">Some tips</h1>

<ul>
  <li>Sometimes you need to do a quick press to the talk button, I really don’t know why…</li>
  <li>You can press and hold BAND button to leave the WiresX or YSF group.</li>
</ul>

<p>I’ll update this entry if I see things changing. 73!</p>]]></content><author><name>Emre Sağlam</name></author><category term="general" /><category term="ham radio" /><category term="yaesu" /><category term="dmr" /><category term="pi-star" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this blog entry I will talk about setting up YSF2DMR on pi-star (on a generic MMDVM device). I’ll try to be brief and not too detailed.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mastodon migration</title><link href="https://blog.emresaglam.com/general/mastodon-migration/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mastodon migration" /><published>2022-10-12T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-10-12T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://blog.emresaglam.com/general/mastodon-migration</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.emresaglam.com/general/mastodon-migration/"><![CDATA[<p>I did a thing today and I opened a Mastodon account. I was never very active on Twitter, I will probably not be very active on Mastodon, but here is to support open standards! :)</p>

<p>I’m interested in the decentralized way of Mastodon’s inner workings. Having a “local instance” is also very neighborhoodly so far. I already switched two servers and it went smooth.</p>

<p>Here is my <a href="https://infosec.exchange/@emresaglam"><i class="fab fa-fw fa-mastodon"></i>Mastodon link</a> or <a href="https://infosec.exchange/@emresaglam">@emresaglam@infosec.exchange</a>. Follow me, or not…</p>]]></content><author><name>Emre Sağlam</name></author><category term="general" /><category term="social media" /><category term="life" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I did a thing today and I opened a Mastodon account. I was never very active on Twitter, I will probably not be very active on Mastodon, but here is to support open standards! :)]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How to change your auxiliary battery on your LR4</title><link href="https://blog.emresaglam.com/general/how-to-change-your-auxiliary-battery-on-your-lr4/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to change your auxiliary battery on your LR4" /><published>2020-12-06T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2020-12-06T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>https://blog.emresaglam.com/general/how-to-change-your-auxiliary-battery-on-your-lr4</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.emresaglam.com/general/how-to-change-your-auxiliary-battery-on-your-lr4/"><![CDATA[<p>I probably am one of the few who likes the ECO functionality on my LR4. You stop, the engine stops. Simple. Until it doesn’t…</p>

<p>One thing we learned from the hybrid vehicles is that we can efficiently and automatically start stop gas engines using an auxiliary battery. With hybrid vehicles having a huge battery capacity, not a big deal… With normal gas engines with a tiny battery, well… things don’t go as well as the hybrid ones. :(</p>

<p>Very first sign of a malfunctioning battery is the orange, crossed out ECO sign with a circular arrow on it. This means either your battery is running low, or already dead. If after long drives it disappears, it means it’s still charging. But trust me it’ll die soon.</p>

<p>The battery is a “special battery” by Land Rover. From the size of it, it looks like a motorcycle battery. The part number is: CX23-10C655-AC or LR047630. Exide makes them. You can get a Jaguar/Land Rover branded one, or an Exide branded one. Up to you. As you can see I chose a branded one. I ordered mine online from <a href="https://www.centurylandroverhuntsville.com">Land Rover of Huntsville</a>. Super fast delivery. Kudos to them!</p>

<p>Here is how to replace your battery.</p>

<ul>
  <li>Pop out your plastic engine cover. It’s the one on the driver side. (For driving on the right side of the road people) Pull the tab and it’ll pop right out. Check out the picture (before/after) Also remove that gray styrofoam cover. That’s where the battery is.</li>
</ul>

<table>
	<tr>
		<td><a href="/assets/img/IMG_0314.jpeg"><img src="/assets/img/IMG_0314.jpeg" /></a></td>
		<td><a href="/assets/img/IMG_0315.jpeg"><img src="/assets/img/IMG_0315.jpeg" /></a></td>
		<td><a href="/assets/img/IMG_0316.jpeg"><img src="/assets/img/IMG_0316.jpeg" /></a></td>
	</tr>
</table>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Prepare your 10 mm socket and a long(ish) socket arm. The battery holder’s nut is pretty deep. This is where you probably need a magnetic socket. I didn’t have one, I survived :) Same socket opens the battery terminal nuts too. You don’t need to completely unscrew them. Just loosen them enough to pop the terminals. Don’t make the same mistake I did.</p>

    <p>Also there is a black “pipe” with a red piece that connects to the battery (for acide fumes coming out of your battery). Don’t forget to disconnect (and reconnect) that too.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<table>
	<tr>
		<td><a href="/assets/img/IMG_0319.jpeg"><img src="/assets/img/IMG_0319.jpeg" /></a></td>
		<td><a href="/assets/img/IMG_0320.jpeg"><img src="/assets/img/IMG_0320.jpeg" /></a></td>
		<td><a href="/assets/img/IMG_0321.jpeg"><img src="/assets/img/IMG_0321.jpeg" /></a></td>
	</tr>
</table>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>My original battery was covered with a styrofoam-ish wrap. It’s connected to the battery with double sided tape. I gently removed it from the battery and rewrapped the new one with it. Probably another part that the dealer would have charged few hundreds to me :D</p>

    <p>Below you can find the voltage differences between the old and the new battery and a picture of the properly mounted terminals.</p>

    <p>The rest is to mount everything back in reverse! If you don’t have a magnetic socket I feel sorry for you. ;)</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<table>
        <tr>
                <td><a href="/assets/img/IMG_0312.jpeg"><img src="/assets/img/IMG_0312.jpeg" /></a></td>
                <td><a href="/assets/img/IMG_0322.jpeg"><img src="/assets/img/IMG_0322.jpeg" /></a></td>
                <td><a href="/assets/img/IMG_0324.jpeg"><img src="/assets/img/IMG_0324.jpeg" /></a></td>
        </tr>
	<tr>
                <td colspan="3"><a href="/assets/img/IMG_0323.jpeg"><img src="/assets/img/IMG_0323.jpeg" /></a></td>
        </tr>
</table>]]></content><author><name>Emre Sağlam</name></author><category term="general" /><category term="blog" /><category term="life" /><category term="howto" /><category term="fix" /><category term="tips" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I probably am one of the few who likes the ECO functionality on my LR4. You stop, the engine stops. Simple. Until it doesn’t…]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">GE Dishwasher parts nightmare!</title><link href="https://blog.emresaglam.com/general/dishwasher-parts-nightmare/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="GE Dishwasher parts nightmare!" /><published>2020-11-14T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2020-11-14T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>https://blog.emresaglam.com/general/dishwasher-parts-nightmare</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.emresaglam.com/general/dishwasher-parts-nightmare/"><![CDATA[<p>We have a GE dishwasher. Model number: PDWT380R10SS. It’s one of those that has “touch buttons” on the lid.</p>

<p>This one was made in 2009. It’s in its glorious 11th year as I am writing this blog entry. According to <a href="https://www.consumerreports.org/dishwashers/how-to-make-your-dishwasher-last-longer/">Consumer Reports</a>the average life of a dishwasher is 10 years. I already changed the detergent pump of the dishwasher which was clogged because of our mistakes (probably another blog entry).</p>

<p>The “touch buttons” and their LED lights started to fail one by one in the last few years. The last one standing was the Start button (essential functionality). Last week it decided to die too.</p>

<p>I was looking for the part for the last 2 years or so and it is always out of stock. Here is the part number for the “Keypad Assembly”: WD34X11603.</p>

<p>Since we don’t have a functioning dishwasher anymore, I gave a call to GE. Since Covid started they cannot keep up with the parts anymore due to increase of home appliance usage. :( I decided to reverse engineer the buttons. Long story short, I learned a lot how these buttons work but I couldn’t save the keypad assembly.</p>

<p>However I figured out that part number WD34X11587 has actually same connection pattern as WD34X11603! It’s also ~$100 cheaper. It’s missing few “modes” which is totally unused by us anyway. So I ordered it, mounted it and now we have a running dishwasher :)</p>

<p>I hope this helps someone. ;)</p>

<p>Totally unrelated, not really: I ordered this one and few other parts from <a href="http://appliancepartspros.com/">AppliancePartsPros.com</a> and I’m very happy with them. I don’t get paid to write this here. I just like how it was easy and fast. Thanks!</p>]]></content><author><name>Emre Sağlam</name></author><category term="general" /><category term="blog" /><category term="life" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We have a GE dishwasher. Model number: PDWT380R10SS. It’s one of those that has “touch buttons” on the lid.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New Blog!</title><link href="https://blog.emresaglam.com/general/new-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Blog!" /><published>2020-11-08T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2020-11-08T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>https://blog.emresaglam.com/general/new-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.emresaglam.com/general/new-blog/"><![CDATA[<p>I decided to say good bye to Wordpress today. Let’s see if I will regret this decision in the long run. :)</p>

<p>I tried to move my blog to jekyll, mainly because I don’t want to manage a server side software stack (Mainly PHP, Wordpress and MYSQL). I said I tried, because I wasn’t successful moving everything that I wrote since 2003.</p>

<p>As some of you might know, I had my blog running on 3 different platform in the past years (and this is the 4th) Out of those, first two were written by me. The last one was Wordpress. Because of all these moves, my blog was in a miserable state. Because of these inconsistencies, I really had hard time moving my entire blog to the new jekyll generated github pages.</p>

<p>So, I decided to import everything from 2016 to today (My most inactive years!) and leave the rest (mostly immature ramblings) in <a href="https://archive.emresaglam.com/">https://archive.emresaglam.com</a></p>

<p>Maybe in the future I might move it under the same domain. But not now. :) Here is to the new beginnings! :P</p>]]></content><author><name>Emre Sağlam</name></author><category term="general" /><category term="blog" /><category term="life" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I decided to say good bye to Wordpress today. Let’s see if I will regret this decision in the long run. :)]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Apple watch radio</title><link href="https://blog.emresaglam.com/general/apple-watch-radio/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Apple watch radio" /><published>2020-05-01T20:16:36-07:00</published><updated>2020-05-01T20:16:36-07:00</updated><id>https://blog.emresaglam.com/general/apple-watch-radio</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.emresaglam.com/general/apple-watch-radio/"><![CDATA[<p>If you’re like me and you have the radio app not working and your Apple Watch is saying: “Sign in to your Apple ID in General in the Apple Watch app on your iPhone” (And of course you are signed in), this solved my issue.</p>

<ul>
  <li>Go to “Settings -&gt; iTunes &amp; App Store”</li>
  <li>Tap on your logged in Apple ID.</li>
  <li>Tap Sign Out button.</li>
  <li>Reboot your phone (Just in case!)</li>
  <li>Go back to “Settings -&gt; iTunes &amp; App Store”</li>
  <li>Log back in with your Apple ID</li>
  <li>Go to you Apple Watch and most probably you’ll see Radio working! Hurray!</li>
</ul>

<p>Apple Watch Series 4 just in case. ;)</p>]]></content><author><name>Emre Sağlam</name></author><category term="general" /><category term="apple" /><category term="apple watch" /><category term="tips" /><category term="watch" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you’re like me and you have the radio app not working and your Apple Watch is saying: “Sign in to your Apple ID in General in the Apple Watch app on your iPhone” (And of course you are signed in), this solved my issue.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">So you lost a disk on a MD RAID5 array, now what?</title><link href="https://blog.emresaglam.com/general/so-you-lost-a-disk-on-a-md-raid5-array-now-what/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="So you lost a disk on a MD RAID5 array, now what?" /><published>2020-04-28T16:47:21-07:00</published><updated>2020-04-28T16:47:21-07:00</updated><id>https://blog.emresaglam.com/general/so-you-lost-a-disk-on-a-md-raid5-array-now-what</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.emresaglam.com/general/so-you-lost-a-disk-on-a-md-raid5-array-now-what/"><![CDATA[<p>It happens, you just lost a disk on your RAID5 MD array, or things are not how it should look like… How do we troubleshoot this?</p>

<p>First things first, what’s the name of your MD device. You can easily learn that by issuing:</p>

<div class="language-bash highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="nb">cat</span> /proc/mdstat
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>This should output something similar to:</p>

<div class="language-console highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="go">Personalities : [linear] [multipath] [raid0] [raid1] [raid6] [raid5] [raid4] [raid10]
md0 : active raid5 sdd[1] sda[3] sdb[2]
2929890816 blocks super 1.2 level 5, 512k chunk, algorithm 2 [3/4] [.AAA]
bitmap: 0/8 pages [0KB], 65536KB chunk
</span></code></pre></div></div>

<p>Here we have a MD device <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">/dev/md0</code>. (If you don’t see a response to this, you might have lost your MD device, which could be a bigger issue!)</p>

<p>Another thing that we see (Or we don’t see) here is that sda/sdb/sdd are here in the raid but <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">sdc</code> is nowhere to be found! This is our problem.</p>

<p>For some reason <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">/dev/sdc</code> is not in the RAID group anymore. Let’s see what’s going on with <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">/dev/sdc</code>?</p>

<div class="language-bash highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>mdadm <span class="nt">--examine</span> /dev/sdc
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>In my example this was hanging for a long time. When I issue <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">dmesg</code> on another console, I was getting a lot of I/O errors about this disk. This is telling me that the disk is malfunctioning.</p>

<p>I shutdown the server and wiggled the disk. Rebooted and it was back online. My array has now four disks however only 3 of them are “functioning” since after the reboot MD kicked <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">/dev/sdc</code> out of the array.</p>

<p>We need to reassemble the array and let RAID5 do its magic. First stop the MD device <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">/dev/md0</code>.</p>

<div class="language-bash highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>mdadm <span class="nt">--stop</span> /dev/md0
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Then we need to add <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">/dev/sdc</code> back into the array:</p>

<div class="language-bash highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>mdadm /dev/md0 <span class="nt">-a</span> /dev/sdc
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Then depending on the situation we might need to reassemble the array:</p>

<div class="language-bash highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>mdadm <span class="nt">--assemble</span> /dev/md0 /dev/sd[abcd] <span class="nt">--verbose</span> <span class="nt">--force</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Hopefully <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">/dev/sdc</code> is now back in your array now. This should start a long(er) process to sync up the array state to all disks and hopefully you now have your array back!</p>

<p>After the sync completes, I would still do a fsck on the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">/dev/md0</code> filesystem.</p>

<div class="language-bash highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="nv">$ </span>fsck.ext4 /dev/md0
e2fsck 1.45.5 <span class="o">(</span>07-Jan-2020<span class="o">)</span>
data: recovering journal
JBD2: Invalid checksum recovering block 185073680 <span class="k">in </span>log
JBD2: Invalid checksum recovering block 89 <span class="k">in </span>log
Journal checksum error found <span class="k">in </span>data
data was not cleanly unmounted, check forced.
Pass 1: Checking inodes, blocks, and sizes
Pass 2: Checking directory structure
Pass 3: Checking directory connectivity
Pass 4: Checking reference counts
Pass 5: Checking group summary information
Free blocks count wrong <span class="o">(</span>704006059, <span class="nv">counted</span><span class="o">=</span>696320594<span class="o">)</span><span class="nb">.</span>
Fix? <span class="nb">yes
</span>Free inodes count wrong <span class="o">(</span>182701042, <span class="nv">counted</span><span class="o">=</span>182694547<span class="o">)</span><span class="nb">.</span>
Fix? <span class="nb">yes
 </span>data: FILE SYSTEM WAS MODIFIED
data: 429421/183123968 files <span class="o">(</span>0.2% non-contiguous<span class="o">)</span>, 36152110/732472704 blocks
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>You can use this same steps (or similar) to remove /dev/sdc and replace with a brand new hard drive. In my case wiggling solved the problem for now. (I probably will need a drive in the near future)</p>

<p>I hope this helped someone. It surely will help me when I will have to do this again 😛</p>]]></content><author><name>Emre Sağlam</name></author><category term="General" /><category term="linux" /><category term="tips" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It happens, you just lost a disk on your RAID5 MD array, or things are not how it should look like… How do we troubleshoot this?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Run pihole without raspberry pi</title><link href="https://blog.emresaglam.com/general/run-pihole-without-raspberry-pi/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Run pihole without raspberry pi" /><published>2019-11-16T10:38:02-08:00</published><updated>2019-11-16T10:38:02-08:00</updated><id>https://blog.emresaglam.com/general/run-pihole-without-raspberry-pi</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.emresaglam.com/general/run-pihole-without-raspberry-pi/"><![CDATA[<p>I have few 24/7 running linux boxes at home. I wanted to try <a href="https://pi-hole.net">pi-hole</a>. But I really didn’t want to add another computer (raspberry pi) on my network.</p>

<p>So my initial feeling was why not try Docker? Good choice. Here is how easy it was.</p>

<p>Pull pihole docker image</p>

<div class="language-bash highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="nv">$ </span>docker pull pihole/pihole
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Find your local IP (Replace eth0 with your ethernet identifier)</p>

<div class="language-bash highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="nv">$ </span><span class="nb">sudo </span>ip addr show eth0 | <span class="nb">grep</span> <span class="s2">"inet</span><span class="se">\\</span><span class="s2">b"</span> | <span class="nb">awk</span> <span class="s1">'{print $2}'</span> | <span class="nb">cut</span> <span class="nt">-d</span> <span class="s2">"/"</span> <span class="nt">-f</span> 1
192.168.0.100
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Get the IP (192.168.0.100 in my case) and run docker:</p>

<div class="language-bash highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="nv">$ </span>docker run <span class="nt">-d</span> <span class="nt">--name</span> pihole <span class="nt">-e</span> <span class="nv">ServerIP</span><span class="o">=</span>192.168.0.100 <span class="nt">-e</span> <span class="nv">WEBPASSWORD</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="s2">"myawesomepassword"</span> <span class="nt">-e</span> <span class="nv">DNS1</span><span class="o">=</span>8.8.8.8 <span class="nt">-p</span> 9080:80 <span class="nt">-p</span> 53:53/tcp <span class="nt">-p</span> 53:53/udp <span class="nt">-p</span> 9443:443 pihole/pihole:latest
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Here in this example above I’m using myawesomepassword as login password to pihole (Change it to your password). I connect the host OS port 9080 to pihole’s port 80 and 9443 to pihole’s port 443.</p>

<p>DNS server is running on port 53. (Since I’m not doing any zone transfer I can leave TCP 53 out, but oh well ¯\_(ツ)_/¯ )</p>

<p>You can login to the admin interface in <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">http://192.168.100:9080/admin</code> and start setting your pihole up.</p>

<p>Have fun blocking pesky DNS requests ;)</p>]]></content><author><name>Emre Sağlam</name></author><category term="general" /><category term="dns" /><category term="docker" /><category term="linux" /><category term="pihole" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I have few 24/7 running linux boxes at home. I wanted to try pi-hole. But I really didn’t want to add another computer (raspberry pi) on my network.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">shadowsocks auto deploy</title><link href="https://blog.emresaglam.com/general/security/shadowsocks-auto-deploy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="shadowsocks auto deploy" /><published>2018-04-06T09:37:58-07:00</published><updated>2018-04-06T09:37:58-07:00</updated><id>https://blog.emresaglam.com/general/security/shadowsocks-auto-deploy</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.emresaglam.com/general/security/shadowsocks-auto-deploy/"><![CDATA[<p>I wrote a <a href="http://cloudinit.readthedocs.io/en/latest/index.html">cloud-init</a> script to automate the deployment of a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shadowsocks">shadowsocks server</a>. I shared it <a href="https://gist.github.com/emresaglam/e1e442791cd5b3841b3159c0b9f071e4">in a gist here</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Features:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Creates a non-privileged user
<ul>
<li>Uploads your ssh public key to the user</li>
<li>Adds this user to the sudoers group</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Disables ssh login for the root user</li>
<li>Downloads and installs libraries required for <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Salsa20#ChaCha20_adoption">chacha20</a></li>
<li>Creates a "random" password and writes it in the config.json file</li>
<li>config.json file is in the /root directory. (You will need the password in this config file to be able to connect to your shadowsocks server.)</li>
<li>Starts the shadowsocks server.</li>
</ul>
<p>You have to fill out the _YOURUSERNAMEHERE_, _YOURSSHPUBLICKEYHERE_ and _YOURFULLNAMEHERE_ with your data.</p>
<p>You can use this script in DigitalOcean easily following<a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-use-cloud-config-for-your-initial-server-setup"> this document</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name>Emre Sağlam</name></author><category term="general" /><category term="security" /><category term="linux" /><category term="security" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I wrote a cloud-init script to automate the deployment of a shadowsocks server. I shared it in a gist here. Features: Creates a non-privileged user Uploads your ssh public key to the user Adds this user to the sudoers group Disables ssh login for the root user Downloads and installs libraries required for chacha20 Creates a "random" password and writes it in the config.json file config.json file is in the /root directory. (You will need the password in this config file to be able to connect to your shadowsocks server.) Starts the shadowsocks server. You have to fill out the _YOURUSERNAMEHERE_, _YOURSSHPUBLICKEYHERE_ and _YOURFULLNAMEHERE_ with your data. You can use this script in DigitalOcean easily following this document.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Air Quality Index Bot</title><link href="https://blog.emresaglam.com/general/air_quality_index_bot/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Air Quality Index Bot" /><published>2017-10-16T21:09:45-07:00</published><updated>2017-10-16T21:09:45-07:00</updated><id>https://blog.emresaglam.com/general/air_quality_index_bot</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://blog.emresaglam.com/general/air_quality_index_bot/"><![CDATA[<p>After the devastating Northern California wildfires, I found myself looking at <a href="http://airnow.gov/" title="Airnow">AirNow</a> multiple times a day. Also at work, like many Bay Area tech companies, we use HipChat (or Slack). Naturally I was inclined to issue a slash command to get the latest air quality index (AQI) for my area in a chat channel. I couldn’t find a good AQI bot so I wrote one.</p>

<p><a href="/assets/img/Screen-Shot-2017-10-16-at-9.19.51-PM.png"><img src="/assets/img/Screen-Shot-2017-10-16-at-9.19.51-PM.png" alt="Example bot blabber" title="Bot blabber" /></a></p>

<p>Installation for Heroku is on the README of the project. How to add a slash command for HipChat and/or Slack are not covered in this blog entry, but it’s very easy :) (I used /aq &lt;zipcode&gt; for command)</p>

<p>The bot (really an API endpoint) <a href="https://github.com/emresaglam/airbot">is here in my github repo</a>. Feel free to use, improve, contribute to it.</p>]]></content><author><name>Emre Sağlam</name></author><category term="general" /><category term="api" /><category term="git" /><category term="github" /><category term="opensource" /><category term="project" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[After the devastating Northern California wildfires, I found myself looking at AirNow multiple times a day. Also at work, like many Bay Area tech companies, we use HipChat (or Slack). Naturally I was inclined to issue a slash command to get the latest air quality index (AQI) for my area in a chat channel. I couldn’t find a good AQI bot so I wrote one.]]></summary></entry></feed>